export default {
  id: 'low_1006_1_1a',
  name: '상용한자(1학년/음독찾기)',
  data: [
    { question: '一', answer: ['한 일', 'ひと、ひと(つ)', 'いち、いつ'] },
    { question: '二', answer: ['두 이', 'ふた、ふた(つ)', 'に'] },
    { question: '三', answer: ['석 삼', 'み、み(つ)、みっ(つ)', 'さん'] },
    { question: '四', answer: ['넉 사', 'よ、よ(つ)、よっ(つ)、よん', 'し'] },
    { question: '五', answer: ['다섯 오', 'いつ、いつ(つ)', 'ご'] },
    { question: '六', answer: ['여섯 육', 'む、むい、む(つ)、むっ(つ)', 'ろく'] },
    { question: '七', answer: ['일곱 칠', 'なな、なな(つ)、[なの]', 'しち'] },
    { question: '八', answer: ['여덟 팔', 'や、や(つ)、やっ(つ)、[よう]', 'はち'] },
    { question: '九', answer: ['아홉 구', 'ここの、ここの(つ)', 'く、きゅう'] },
    { question: '十', answer: ['열 십', 'と、とお', 'じゅう、じっ'] },
    { question: '百', answer: ['일백 백', '', 'ひゃく'] },
    { question: '千', answer: ['일천 천', 'ち', 'せん'] },
    { question: '年', answer: ['해 년', 'とし', 'ねん'] },
    { question: '日', answer: ['날 일', 'ひ、か', 'にち、じつ'] },
    { question: '月', answer: ['달 월', 'つき', 'げつ、がつ'] },
    { question: '火', answer: ['불 화', 'ひ、[ほ]', 'か'] },
    { question: '水', answer: ['물 수', 'みず', 'すい'] },
    { question: '木', answer: ['나무 목', 'き、[こ]', 'もく、ぼく'] },
    { question: '金', answer: ['쇠 금', 'かね、かな', 'きん、こん'] },
    { question: '土', answer: ['흙 토', 'つち', 'ど、と'] },
    { question: '上', answer: ['윗 상', 'うえ、[うわ]、かみ、あ(げる)、あ(がる)、のぼ(る)、のぼ(せる)、のぼ(す)', 'じょう、[しょう]'] },
    { question: '下', answer: ['아래 하', 'した、しも、もと、さ(げる)、さ(がる)、くだ(る)、くだ(す)、くだ(さる)、お(りる)、お(ろす)', 'か、げ'] },
    { question: '大', answer: ['큰 대', 'おお、おお(きい)、おお(いに)', 'だい、たい'] },
    { question: '中', answer: ['가운데 중', 'なか', 'ちゅう、[じゅう]'] },
    { question: '小', answer: ['작을 소', 'ちい(さい)、こ、お', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '左', answer: ['왼 좌', 'ひだり', 'さ'] },
    { question: '右', answer: ['오른 우', 'みぎ', 'う、ゆう'] },
    { question: '白', answer: ['흰 백', 'しろ、[しら]、しろ(い)', 'はく、びゃく'] },
    { question: '赤', answer: ['붉을 적', 'あか、あか(い)、あか(らむ)、あか(らめる)', 'せき、[しゃく]'] },
    { question: '青', answer: ['푸를 청', 'あお、あお(い)', 'せい、[しょう]'] },
    { question: '口', answer: ['입 구', 'くち', 'こう、く'] },
    { question: '耳', answer: ['귀 이', 'みみ', 'じ'] },
    { question: '目', answer: ['눈 목', 'め、[ま]', 'もく、[ぼく]'] },
    { question: '手', answer: ['손 수', 'て、[た]', 'しゅ'] },
    { question: '足', answer: ['발 족', 'あし、た(りる)、た(る)、た(す)', 'そく'] },
    { question: '文', answer: ['글월 문', 'ふみ', 'ぶん、もん'] },
    { question: '字', answer: ['글자 자', 'あざ', 'じ'] },
    { question: '先', answer: ['먼저 선', 'さき', 'せん'] },
    { question: '生', answer: ['날 생', 'い(きる)、い(かす)、い(ける)、う(まれる)、う(む)、お(う)、は(える)、は(やす)、なま、き', 'せい、しょう'] },
    { question: '学', answer: ['배울 학', 'まな(ぶ)', 'がく'] },
    { question: '校', answer: ['학교 교', '학교', 'こう'] },
    { question: '車', answer: ['수레 차(거)', 'くるま', 'しゃ'] },
    { question: '出', answer: ['날 출', 'で(る)、だ(す)', 'しゅつ、[すい]'] },
    { question: '入', answer: ['들 입', 'い(る)、い(れる)、はい(る)', 'にゅう'] },
    { question: '山', answer: ['뫼 산', 'やま', 'さん'] },
    { question: '川', answer: ['내 천', 'かわ', 'せん'] },
    { question: '天', answer: ['하늘 천', '[あま]、あめ', 'てん'] },
    { question: '石', answer: ['돌 석', 'いし', 'せき、[しゃく]、[こく]'] },
    { question: '森', answer: ['수풀 삼', 'もり', 'しん'] },
    { question: '林', answer: ['수풀 림', 'はやし', 'りん'] },
    { question: '空', answer: ['빌 공', 'そら、あ(く)、あ(ける)、から', 'くう'] },
    { question: '気', answer: ['기운 기', '기운', 'き、け'] },
    { question: '雨', answer: ['비 우', 'あめ、(あま)', 'う'] },
    { question: '夕', answer: ['저녁 석', 'ゆう', 'せき'] },
    { question: '男', answer: ['사내 남', 'おとこ', 'だん、なん'] },
    { question: '女', answer: ['여자 녀', 'おんな、め', 'じょ、にょ、[にょう]'] },
    { question: '人', answer: ['사람 인', 'ひと', 'じん、にん'] },
    { question: '名', answer: ['이름 명', 'な', 'めい、みょう'] },
    { question: '王', answer: ['임금 왕', '임금', 'おう'] },
    { question: '子', answer: ['아들 자', 'こ', 'し、す'] },
    { question: '力', answer: ['힘 력', 'ちから', 'りょく、りき'] },
    { question: '正', answer: ['바를 정', 'ただ(しい)、ただ(す)、まさ', 'せい、しょう'] },
    { question: '犬', answer: ['개 견', 'いぬ', 'けん'] },
    { question: '虫', answer: ['벌레 충', 'むし', 'ちゅう'] },
    { question: '貝', answer: ['조개 패', '조개', 'かい'] },
    { question: '花', answer: ['꽃 화', 'はな', 'か'] },
    { question: '草', answer: ['풀 초', 'くさ', 'そう'] },
    { question: '竹', answer: ['대 죽', 'たけ', 'ちく'] },
    { question: '円', answer: ['둥글 원', 'まる(い)', 'えん'] },
    { question: '玉', answer: ['구슬 옥', 'たま', 'ぎょく'] },
    { question: '糸', answer: ['실 사', 'いと', 'し'] },
    { question: '見', answer: ['볼 견', 'み(る)、み(える)、み(せる)', 'けん'] },
    { question: '音', answer: ['소리 음', 'おと、ね', 'おん、いん'] },
    { question: '休', answer: ['쉴 휴', 'やす(む)、やす(まる)、やす(める)', 'きゅう'] },
    { question: '本', answer: ['근본 본', 'もと', 'ほん'] },
    { question: '立', answer: ['설 립', 'た(つ)、た(てる)', 'りつ、[りゅう]'] },
    { question: '早', answer: ['이를 조', 'はや(い)、はや(まる)、はや(める)', 'そう、[さっ]'] },
    { question: '田', answer: ['밭 전', 'た', 'でん'] },
    { question: '町', answer: ['밭두둑 정', 'まち', 'ちょう'] },
    { question: '村', answer: ['마을 촌', 'むら', 'そん'] }
  ]
}
